Afonso Almendra Praça de Carvalho

Brazilian, 28 years, married

Rua Teresa Guimarães 83, casa 9 - Botafogo - Rio de Janeiro - RJ - CEP: 22280-050 +55 21 3495.1850 // +55 21 97915.1515 afonsoinfo@gmail.com http://afonsopraca.com.br/

Summary

A brazilian software developer based in Rio de Janeiro, currently working for VTEX - E-commerce Cloud Application, a plataform that sells software as a service (SaaS). Mainly focused on front-end development, strongly skilled in JavaScript, and now working and searching mostly with AngularJS. Knows the e-commerce businnes.

Afonso started working as developer around 2005, as a freelancer developer. In 2009 he began working as lead developer at Caos! Design, where he solidified his knowledge of ActionScript and JavaScript, becoming later a partner of the business. Since 2012 works as a front end developer of VTEX, working mostly in front end of the administration area of the e-commerce apps.

Experience

• Front End Developer at VTEX

July 2012 - Present (1 year 8 months)

Designs and develops JS Apps for E-commerce Suite. Participated in the development of various applications of e-commerce platform, developing the front end of the administration area of the apps. With a Strongly customer centric approach.

- Business Partner and Lead Developer at Caos! vídeo & design
 June 2009 June 2012 (3 years 1 month)
 Led the development of several websites. With attention to detail and commitment to quality.
- System Administrador at Ceperj RJ May 2008 - May 2009 (1 year 1 month) Network and System Administrator

Languages

- English (Professional working proficiency)
- Portuguese (Native or bilingual proficiency)

Projects

• Administrative area of apps that composes the VTEX Commerce Suite

July 2012 to Present

Knockout and AngularJS Apps that consume data from REST APIs. Using Node.js as development support layer. HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap.

Role: Front End Developer

• Penedo RJ - Guia de Restaurantes

January 2012 to Present

AngularJS, Node.js, Express, HTML, CSS and Bootstrap

Role: **Lead Developer** http://penedorj.com.br/

• Todo Dia Arquitetura

October 2012 to December 2012 JS, HTML, CSS and Wordpress

Role: **Lead Developer**

http://tododiaarquitetura.com.br/

Portal Portinari

May 2012 to June 2012

JS, HTML, CSS

Role: **Developer**

http://www.portinari.org.br/

• Guerra e Paz

November 2010 to December 2010

ActionScript 3.

Role: Lead Developer

http://www.guerraepaz.org.br/

• Tainá 3

February 2010 to April 2010

ActionScript 3, HTML, CSS and Wordpress.

Role: **Lead Developer** http://www.taina3.com.br/

Mosaico Mantiqueira

2010

HTML, CSS, Wordpress Role: **Lead Developer**

http://www.mosaicomantiqueira.org.br/

• APA Serrinha Capelinha

2007

HTML, CSS

Role: Lead Developer

http://www.resende.rj.gov.br/apaserrinhacapelinha/

Skills & Expertise

jQuery, JavaScript, Front-end, E-commerce, AngularJS, HTML, CSS, Git, User Experience, ActionScript, Knockout JS, AJAX, WordPress, Software Development, Databases, User Interface Design, MVC, Web Development, Node.js, Express JS, E-business, SOA, SaaS

Education

- Universidade Federal do Estado do Rio de Janeiro
 Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer Information Systems, 2008 2014
- SENAI-RJ Technology Course, Hardware and Computer Networks, 2005 - 2006
- Colégio Resende Anglo High School, 2002 - 2004

Interests

E-commerce, JavaScript, AngularJS, Software Architecture, SOA, REST APIs, Front-end Development and Project Management.